Glory to the Nation!
Dzhokhar Dudayev's battalion defends Ukraine.
- To say Chechnya, Chechens, Grozny is wrong
and incorrect.
Chechnya is in fact a huge concentration camp.
Russian propaganda created the image of a
Chechen terrorist.
- They eat Russian-speaking children, we were
the first to eat, and then you started.
Grozny will be taken in 3 hours, Ukraine in
3 days.
- We see how the Russian army is fighting
now without Ukrainians.
It looks very bad.
- If we had received such assistance then,
there would have been no such bloodshed in Ukraine today.
- The Soviet government had been breaking
us for 70 years.
Until 89 they were absolutely sure that they
finally succeeded.
And what?
Dzhokhar Dudayev comes and says "Forward,
we are going forward".
As long as at least one of us who disagrees
with them is alive, as long as at least one
of you who disagrees with them is alive, they
will not succeed.
Hail to the heroes
There will be a massacre in Crimea
yet.
Ukraine will still meet Russia on the battlefield.
As long as Russia exists, it will never give
up its ambitions.
Now there is Slavic there under this brand,
they want to crush Ukraine, Belarus again as in the old days.
Johar Dudayev spoke these prophetic words
in 95.
Then people looked at him: "What is he talking
about?
What Ukraine?
What war?
What is he talking about?"
But these words turned out to be prophetic.
At that time he was the president of the independent
republic of Ichkeria.
Ichkeria reduced their appetites, but
did not stop them.
And in this video I will tell you about
Dudayev's battalion, which is fighting for the independence of Ukraine and Ichkeria.
At the start of this video, I ask you to like,
subscribe to the channel and send this video
to your friends so that it is better recommended
and more people learn about Dudayev's battalion.
By the way, friends, it is wrong to say "Chechens",
"Grozny", "Chechnya".
This topic will be discussed a little further.
The Russian leadership throughout its
history, when it was in trouble, ran to sign
treaties that it has never adhered to, will
never adhere to and does not understand what an evil empire Russia is.
Interviewer: Now in Ukraine people often
remember the words of Dudayev, right?
One of the quotes is that Russia will disappear
when the Ukrainian sun rises.
He spoke prophetic words in 95. How do you think he knew all this would happen?
Fighter: Dzhokhar Musayevich Dudayev,
the first president of the Chechen Republic of Ichkeria, was a man ahead of his time.
That is, he became a general not on the parquet. He was a real general, despite the fact that
his nationality would not have allowed him to become a general
but he was able to become
a general of the Soviet Army of Strategic Aviation with his talent, his incredible abilities.
This is, let's say, the elite in any army
in the world. When he said that, he said it as a man
who knew the Russians better than they knew themselves. And what he warned the world about and his
words about the Ukrainian sun and his words about the fact that today the war in Chechnya
is called an internal war, Europe calls an
internal affair of Russia, Europe itself will
become an internal affair of Russia.
And so it happened in principle.
Dzhokhar Dudayev had a great respect for the
Ukrainian people, for Ukraine, and, you know,
probably, even in Ukraine there are few people,
I think, who would believe in Ukrainians so
much, who would believe in the spirit, in
the strength of this nation, its abilities,
its future, and he believed.
And now we see that all those who said that
Kyiv in two days, it was said not only by Russians.
This was also said by European politicians
who believed that it was a matter of a few
days, weeks, months, hours.
No, no, now they say something completely
different.
That is, in Russia all non-Russians are second
class.
You said that his nationality
would not allow him to become a general, but
They have been and will be.
he became a general.
It was among these non-Russians that they
found those who seemed the most loyal to them.
What prevented him?
There is a very nice word in
the Ukrainian language, which Ukrainians explained to me - minority.
That is, in Russia all non-Russians are second class. They have been and will be.
It was among these non-Russians that they found those who seemed the most loyal to them.
But as we see, these loyal people received
education, achieved some goals, but they never
ceased to be Ukrainians, Chechens, and it
was a big surprise for the colonizers.
It seemed to them that here he is a general,
he will do what we say, and then - once he
wanted freedom . Because he always wanted
it.
5:35: Interviewer: Did you see Dudayev?
I was a child, yes, at independence
parades and so on.
I saw it more on TV screens.
Now sometimes I watch it on YouTube and I
can honestly say that the Chechen people are
in such a terrible situation today, because
it is gone.
It was the most terrible wound they inflicted
on the Chechen people.
They deprived them of a leader of such a level.
6:09: Interviewer: Why did he believe in Ukrainians
so much?
Ukrainians fought on your side, did he see
something while communicating with them, or
was there some other story.
6:22 Fighter: The relations between the North
Caucasus and Chechnya, Ukraine are a little
bit longer than just participation in hostilities.
The fact is that during the Holodomor, tens
of thousands of people, fleeing from hunger,
went to the North Caucasus.
There was a special operation of the NKVD,
which was aimed at finding these Ukrainians
and sending them to Siberia.
As I heard from elderly people, these were
those who lived in Donetsk and Luhansk regions.
These people understood that they were being
sent to Siberia to die, they were sent to
freezing temperatures, to inhuman living conditions,
they hid their children with Chechens, they
were taken to the mountains, and the NKVD
was looking for them there.
Children were taught the language at an accelerated
pace so that they knew the Chechen language.
So that when the NKVD officers came and asked
them in Chechen, they could answer.
Many NKVD officers, unfortunately, were also
Chechens.
These children stayed, these children grew
up.
Then, in adulthood, they told us who their
parents were.
We still have very warm relations with Ukrainians.
We always separated Russians from Ukrainians.
And when we came to fight for Chechnya, it
was perceived as a natural process.
7:49 - What are you doing here?
Sashko Bilyi: We defend the freedom of the
Chechen Republic, we fight against Moscow's
aggression.
It was not something strange,
it was our courageous brave people.
Today I hope that in the future, when Chechnya
and the whole North Caucasus will be free,
many Ukrainians will come to us and stay here.
Because I would like to hear the Ukrainian
language, to have restaurants serving Ukrainian
cuisine, to have good warm relations between
the North Caucasus and Ukraine.
We have something to give each other, we have
something to support each other.
I think it just needs to be developed.
We have those relations that will never be
between Russians and Ukrainians, because we
do not treat each other as second-class, as
Russians do.
They fought just as bravely, desperately,
and died.
One close comrade told me a story.
Unfortunately, both among Chechens and Ukrainians
there are those who are infected with this
During the storming of Grozny, Ukrainians
came to the basement of the presidential palace
from the position, carrying their wounded
soldier, and one of those who carried him
colonial imperial propaganda, that they call
their "khokhlas", "churkas", think in these
categories.
I think they will soon leave the historical
arena and we will return to normal existence.
was holding his head in his hands, which were
covered with blood.
In the Chechen language there are no nicknames
for any nations.
And at that time Russian deputies arrived
for negotiations.
This Ukrainian brought his friend into the
operating room, came out, smoked, he had a
That is, you cannot say "Khokhly" to be understood,
you have to say "Ukrainians".
big red beard.
He had a trace of blood on his beard.
A Russian deputy came up, saw a Ukrainian
flag on him, asked "Are you Ukrainian?"
You see, this is very important.
He replied: "Yes, I am Ukrainian".
"So what do you think about what is happening,
what are you doing here?"
9:28 Interviewer: How did Ukrainians prove
themselves then, during the Chechen war?
He answered: "We are here fighting for Ukraine.
What was said about Sashko Bilyi?
While we are fighting here, you will not attack
there.
I swear to you," he said, "the holy jihad
that is going on against you, the holy war,
I heard that they drove the only tank you
had...
Soldier: You know, Ukrainians are very,
very good soldiers.
let's say, is for you to see how well we are
fighting.
We see how the Russian army is fighting now
without Ukrainians.
So when the Ukrainian jihad begins, you will
regret that you were born into this world.
It is very bad.
Ukrainians have always been, are and will
be one of the best soldiers in the world.
And when they fought in Chechnya, they fought
the same way as Chechens fought.
So tell that to Moscow.
Well, we have lived to see the Ukrainian jihad,
the Ukrainian struggle.
And today we can observe how the words of
that Ukrainian fighter turned out to be prophetic.
That it is harder for Russians now than ever.
I think that even in 41 it was not so difficult,
because then they were supported by the United
States, allies and so on.
And now they have treacherously attacked Ukraine
for absolutely no reason, for no reason at
all, to destroy it.
It is not just about the seizure of the country
and territory.
We are talking about Bucha.
This is not some empty words.
Anyone who doubts can go to Bucha.
There will be more to come.
And in the final, Mariupol is waiting for
us.
The country will shudder from the horror,
from the number of deaths they brought to
this land.
Someone can answer the question "Why?".
But simply because there should not be Ukrainians.
They do not recognize the right of the Ukrainian
people to exist.
They do not recognize the right to exist for
the Ukrainian language, culture.
Do you see what they are doing in the occupied
territories?
Do you see how the Ukrainian language is banned?
You will see how they bring Russian teachers.
They are trying to completely eliminate the
nation.
I don't know, I read about such things as
a child in books, when there were some colonial
wars in the 19th century.
And then, I do not know such horror, such
purposeful hatred, terror towards the people.
13:25 Interviewer: I understand that your
people were not surprised by all this, because
what they were doing in Ichkeria, in your
territory, it was give or take the same as
it was then, maybe even worse.
I heard stories when people were torn apart
by tanks, people were boiled...
13:39 A fighter: They do what is normal in
their perception of the world.
The more brutal and horrible the executions,
the destruction of entire cities, villages,
regions, the more chances they have to win.
They are just trying to break the spirit of
the people.
They believe that if they arranged this in
Bucha, Ukrainians, looking at it or Mariupol,
should surrender.
Because they would surrender.
If the invaders behaved the same way towards
them, they would surrender.
But they underestimate the will of neither
Chechen nor Ukrainian people.
Chechens have not signed any act of surrender.
They do not have this piece of paper.
They have no commander-in-chief of the Armed
Forces of Ichkeria or president or acting
president who would sit down and sign the
papers.
Kadyrov is the same Pasichnyk, Zakharchenko,
who was blown up.
That is, this is a "doll" from their environment,
a tame monster.
A dog that they brought, and he is already
pretending to be in power
15:05 Interviewer: Explain how it happened
that a man like his father, like him, was
told to kill as many Russians as possible,
and then he became a leader.
How did this happen?
Did they just sell out or what was the trick?
15:20 Fighter: I think that Ukrainians could
write dissertations on this topic.
Because the number of pro-Russian politicians
in Ukraine who have been calling the occupation,
the annexation a "civil war" all these years,
"it's all for money, someone there arranged
it, it's not our war, it's all the Americans,
the French, God, but not Russia".
Ukrainians saw them every day on their TV
screens.
They heard it every day, every election these
people came out, promised Ukrainians peace,
prosperity and the opportunity to negotiate
with Russia.
So...
These are the same people, do you understand?
If they came to power tomorrow...
Do you think Medvedchuk would behave differently
than Kadyrov?
There are such people in every nation.
His father called for killing 150 Russians,
promised paradise for it.
They are ready to say anything to deceive
you.
Where necessary, they will be the greatest
patriots, but their essence of a traitor does
not change.
I would not even call them traitors.
A traitor is a person who had some ideals,
values and then betrayed them.
And Kadyrov, Medvedchuk and others have never
had such ideals.
They have never respected either Chechnya
or Ukraine.
They did not consider either Chechens or Ukrainians
as nations and people.
They did not believe that we have the right
to
our language, culture, independence, freedom.
They have always been for Russia.
They are pure enemy.
There is no room for doubt.
Just because he speaks Chechen or has Ukrainian
citizenship, a person cannot be considered
a Chechen, a Ukrainian and so on.
As for those who are ready to fight for Ukraine,
to give their lives for it from other countries
and peoples who do not have Ukrainian citizenship...
I have always had a dream that many people
who come here...
For example, just yesterday I read the news
that Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, some other states
announced that those who will fight in Ukraine
will have problems at home.
And those who fight for Ukraine will not be
able to return home.
I do not want to hand out citizenship left
and right, but I would like the Ukrainian
Council, the authorities to make some kind
of passport of honor.
With this passport a person would be able
to live, work, study, fight for this country.
But this person would still understand that
he/she is a guest.
For example, they would not be able to vote
in elections, to be elected, to serve in the
police and special services.
It is like gratitude from the Ukrainian people
to you for fighting.
Live among us, learn, earn money, pay taxes,
follow our laws.
But politics is the work of Ukrainians.
No politician can take a war hero and make
him a deputy.
You know how it works in Ukraine.
I would like very much that no one in the
world would interfere in the internal affairs
of Ukrainians.
ADVERTISING:
Dear viewers, our partners at Favbet have
launched a charity project called "Wheelbarrow
rental" for the Armed Forces of Ukraine.
In order to destroy the enemies more effectively,
our guys and girls at the front need cars
with special functionality.
From each of your deposits, part of the funds
will go to this project.
Thus, 10 vehicles will be assembled and upgraded,
and by the way, one of these vehicles has
probably already been sent to the front at
the moment you are watching this video.
So all this will be covered on a specially
created YouTube channel, the project - all
the details are in the link in the pinned
comment.
Fly there and be inside the game with Favbet.
MAGA
19:43 Interviewer: As far as I understand
it is wrong and incorrect to say the words
"Chechnya", "Chechens", "Grozny".
A fighter: Yes.
Chechen Republic of Ichkeria.
Grozny was a fortress of Tsarist Russia.
The name of the city is Dzhokhar in honor
of the president.
It was the will of the people.
Interviewer: Chechens - how to say it correctly?
A fighter: Nohchi.
Interviewer: What is it from?
Fighter: It means "Chechens" in Chechen.
In general, there is no such word "Chechens"
in our language, it is a Russian word.
Interviewer: Does it offend you when they
call you Chechen?
Fighter: It's just more correct to say "Nohci."
Interviewer: What you see now in terms of
the Russian information space; the fact that
Ukrainians eat Russian children, the language
issue and all these things...
I understand that you have gone through all
these topics.
They also said that they would take Grozny
in 2 hours.
Fighter: Russia has not changed anything at
all.
As they attacked the Chechen Republic of Ichkeria,
they also attacked Ukraine.
Russian-speaking population is oppressed,
Russian-speaking children are eaten.
Interviewer: You were the first to eat.
A fighter: Yes, so we ate first, and then
you started.
Grozny will be taken in 3 hours, Ukraine in
3 days.
Interviewer: The only difference is that the
Russian media in the 90s were pumping up the
theme of Chechen terrorists, these are people
who blow up, blow up, create some chaos.
Ukrainians later became just fascists.
A fighter: Fascists, Nazis.
That is, when you talk to people there today,
the first question is "How is it there?"
For them it is strange that someone lives
in Ukraine.
Like a Chechen lives there, and how so.
They hear about it every day.
As Hitler said, "Tell a lie 100 times, it
will remain a lie.
Tell a lie a million times, and then it will
become the truth".
It is exactly the same here.
Propaganda goes on every day.
You show the same thing, everyone tells you
the same thing, of course, you start to believe
it.
Interviewer: Do you communicate with the Kadyrovites
at all?
Is there any communication, and is it necessary
to communicate with them at all?
Fighter: No, we have no communication.
And in general, there can be no communication
with them.
Just as Ukrainians cannot have communication
with separatists.
This is a person who sees everything and participates
in the destruction of the Chechen and Ukrainian
peoples.
He understands everything perfectly, he knows
what he is doing.
There is no point in explaining anything to
him and talking to him.
Interviewer: I know that there were attempts
on Kadyrov's life.
His bodyguard tried to eliminate him.
That is, there were some movements to overthrow
him.
A fighter: It was a long time ago.
But it was the initiative of this guy himself.
Special services found it out.
He was tortured and beaten for a long time.
According to people, in the end he was fed
to a lion.
Ramzan loves all kinds of zoos there, he has
a palace.
Interviewer: I understand that even if Kadyrov
is gone tomorrow, there will still be his
relatives.
There are a lot of people who are close to
him.
His nephews who are already preparing to take
his place after him.
A fighter: Sure.
There are even his right-hand men, his close
ones.
There are always traitors who are constantly
trying to show themselves, to achieve something.
Russia takes traitors from those people whom
no one notices during the seizure of territory
and who are nobody.
When you give them power and everything in
general, they are ready to do anything just
not to lose it.
And they found such people in Ukraine, when
they seized the territory, and in Chechnya.
Interviewer: I heard that his grandfather
was also a traitor during the Soviet times.
A fighter: Yes, this is a person who received
awards from the Soviet government during the
exile of the people.
Not combat awards, but during peacetime.
They say that the people were traitors, collaborated
with the Nazis, we were not given awards,
but his grandfather received them.
Interviewer: In Ukraine, people often laugh
at Kadyrov when he says "Don, don, don"
A fighter: In the beginning, after his father
died, he became the main puppet, nobody understood
him at all.
If you watch his old videos, you will see
that he mumbles something and nothing is clear.
After that he started working on his pronunciation.
With teachers, most likely, I don't know.
But more or less only now it became clear.
But he comes up with some phrases that no
one understands - neither Chechens, nor Ukrainians,
nor Russians.
Interviewer: Don don this?
Fighter: It's like the word parasite, which
means "There is such a thing."
It's like a confirmation of your words.
Interviewer: Why do you call it a cradle?
I read that there is such a nickname...
A fighter: Lulya, yes, because he is nobody.
He is not someone either militarily or as
a man.
He is just a puppet, the Russian army is behind
him.
Lyulya is an affectionate and humiliating
nickname.
As Doku Umarov said, "It's a pity to waste
even a bullet on him.
We should throw explosives at him so that
he dies of fear".
Interviewer: What are the moods in Grozny
now, given the mobilization?
After they were crushed near Kyiv, mothers,
women did not expect this.
Soldier: You know, there was a video on YouTube,
I don't know if it's deleted now or not, a
woman, when her son was sent back at the beginning
of this war said this.
She was standing, crying, all the relatives
gathered.
Women were crying.
One could not stand it and started screaming:
"If we had rebelled in our time, our sons
would not be sent to war today".
This is the mood of the people.
Of course, it is very difficult to talk about
it there.
They can take your family.
When you see that they can do anything with
women in your house, with the elderly, with
children.
People have nothing sacred, no human concepts.
Obviously, it is difficult for you to do something.
Interviewer: I would like to ask about your
actions here, specifically about Dudayev's
battalion in Ukraine.
With the beginning of the full-scale invasion
you became an assault group.
A soldier: It was during the second offensive
of the Russian occupation army.
At first, we worked as a sabotage group, carried
out reconnaissance.
We transmitted data to the artillery.
When we started to move forward, we became
a reconnaissance and assault group.
Interviewer: You were in Kyiv region and now
you were liberating part of Kharkiv region,
right?
Fighter: Emotions are certainly hard to see.
Civilians, when you walk through a liberated
city or village.
It is hard to see these people crying, but
they greet you with a smile.
On the other hand, you are happy that you
are the one who is taking part in this, and
you hope that you will be the one who will
end this bloodshed and get to the end of it
all.
Interviewer: Have you asked yourself the question
"Why are you here?
Why are you fighting in Ukraine?"
The main motivation.
Fighter: Our motivation is freedom.
The freedom of our people.
I believe that the freedom of the Ukrainian
people depends on the freedom of the Chechen
people.
We have more in common with the Ukrainian
people than with Russians.
Our mentality is similar, we are ready to
give a lot for freedom.
There is an Afghan proverb: "When preparing
for war, prepare 9 bullets: 8 for traitors,
one for the enemy".
The biggest enemy is a traitor.
From the enemy you know what to expect, you
can meet him on the battlefield.
But a traitor will eat you from the inside.
ADVERTISING
31:43 Interviewer: It was quite difficult
to arrange an interview, because the guys
from Dudayev's battalion are quite cautious
and closed.
Plus, we had to wait, because they participated
in the counteroffensive in Kharkiv region.
Now we are going to leave.
This is not a football training, but a military
training.
They say it will be very interesting, but
we need to travel a bit.
I will not say where we are going, it is a
matter of security, it is clear.
Before that, we will stop at the gas station.
By the way, now, choosing any service, I analyze
how this company behaves during the war.
OKKO, where we are now stopping, is very proactive
in terms of how they support our army, our
soldiers, and this is extremely important
now.
For you to understand, since the beginning
of the full-scale war, this company has allocated
more than 120 million hryvnias for various
charitable projects.
One of such projects is "Warming the defenders".
Since the first days of the war OKKO has been
treating defenders for free near the hot spots.
OKKO prepared more than 300 thousand servings
of coffee and 200 thousand hot dogs for our
military.
They often do not have the opportunity to
spend much time to have a snack.
Therefore, such a quick and tasty snack at
the gas station can recharge the military
forces to continue to defend the country.
By the way, friends.
Each of you can transfer your points from
the application "Chip" for coffee and hot
dogs for our heroes.
This can be done very simply in the mobile
application or connect a cashier and he will
tell you everything.
We respect the companies that proactively
behave in the context of supporting our army.
And now we are going to visit our heroes.
Don't forget to like and subscribe to the
channel, right?
Because it is very important.
33:36
Interviewer: We are at the training of Dudayev's
battalion.
They have a football theme, Cooper's test
and many interesting tasks ahead.
Training of new recruits Physical endurance
Fire training Stress resistance Tactical elements
First aid
34:32 Interviewer: Listen, very serious physical
training, I see.
Do you take it very seriously?
The title is MAGA.
A fighter: Yes, of course.
You get tired much faster on the battlefield.
We are slowly preparing ourselves.
We also prepare new recruits for the same
conditions.
They walk and shoot nearby to make them feel
closer to combat conditions.
Firecrackers are like explosions nearby.
Of course, it is difficult to compare with
a real battle, but more or less a person will
be ready for stress.
35:10 Interviewer: Your previous generation,
who fought in the first and second Chechen
wars, is an example for you.
They had no time to prepare.
A fighter: Yes, they had nothing: no weapons,
nothing.
They won these battles purely due to their
spirit and went to the end.
Today it is essentially a very easy war for
us.
Looking at them, I would be ashamed to sit
somewhere.
Because this whole history of our people is
built on the resistance to the occupier.
All our heroes who exist and existed - they
all fought against this empire.
We do not have a single hero who fought somewhere
else.
Everyone fought against this occupier.
35:56 Interviewer: You told me that during
the Chechen war there was a moment when people
asked Dudayev "Where are our weapons?"
A fighter: Yes.
Interviewer: And what did he say?
A fighter: The answer was: the Russian army
is coming, they have a lot of weapons, take
them away.
No one started to resent it.
They accepted it.
And they began to take weapons from the dead
occupiers, or simply take them from the living.
In Grozny, there were battles: a video where
a crowd of people is running after a Russian
to take away weapons.
Interviewer: Still so strong in battle, why?
A fighter: You know, it's in our blood.
Our ancestors fought, it is in our genes to
fight for our freedom.
Just like Ukrainians.
Europe did not expect that Ukraine would survive.
Many who fled Ukraine thought that it was
the end.
But Ukrainians proved that they can fight
even before the support from Europe.
And Europe helped only when Ukraine had already
defended most of the areas at the front.
Where it stopped the army and the occupiers
retreated.
.
Interviewer: What will the mobilization in
the Russian Federation change now?
You are talking now with people who are in
Ichkeria.
What do you think it will change?
A fighter: More blood.
This will change the fact that they want to
reduce as much as possible the number of people
who will go to the resistance.
Kadyrov's loyalists are not the first to go.
For example, the husbands of women who protested,
they will go first.
We tell those people who are forcibly sending
others that they can surrender, that they
will be treated well.
It is not like being captured by the Russian
occupier.
Of course, they are told that they are tortured
and killed there.
There was such a case: Kadyrovites were shown
a video of Ukrainians torturing Russian prisoners.
Then they showed a video where they cut Russian
soldiers.
A Kadyrovite who was sitting in the back said:
"Oh, that's my uncle".
These same Kadyrovites themselves stain Chechens.
They cut off the heads ofjournalists, they
were not found.
Kadyrovites serve Russia in order to blacken
the name of Chechens, among other things.
Interviewer: Do your people have a sense of
blood revenge?
That is, when Ichkeria is liberated, will
you figure out who was doing what?
A fighter: Of course.
Our ancestors made these mistakes every time.
No matter how much Russia tries to denigrate
us, to say how terrible and terrible we are,
but at the moment when victory has come, everyone
does not want to kill anymore.
They want peace and finally to leave it all
behind, to live a peaceful life.
Each time the same thing was repeated.
We left these traitors...
We are one people, we must live together.
We talked to them.
Everything was forgotten.
And then Russia prepared the same people.
They sowed discord.
And it all started again.
Therefore, we must get rid of traitors by
any means.
There is no other way out.
No nation has ever gained freedom without
getting rid of traitors.
There is no such thing.
Traitors today betray and will betray again.
Such people cannot be trusted.
The occupiers themselves write in the document
"prone to betrayal" on the people who work
for them.
They themselves do not perceive them as people.
These are people who, if anything, are ready
to switch sides.
Interviewer: Are you ready to take into the
battalion those people who were mobilized
but surrendered?
Theoretically.
Fighter: Yes, of course, only will be checked.
Where, what, did you participate in the Chechen
war on the side of the occupiers?
Were the fighters in the resistance?
All this will be taken into account.
There must be strict control over this.
Interviewer: Did you talk about this in your
battalion?
A fighter: Of course.
And if people who were sent here by threatening
their families.
In captivity they will be exchanged and sent
back home.
So what is better for them - to die defenseless
among the occupiers or to die defending freedom
of speech?
A dead lion is more valuable than a live jackal.
Interviewer: Is your dream to return to Free
Ichkeria?
I am a fighter: I am the son of a fighter
who fought in the first and second Chechen
war.
I continue the work of my father.
We will all continue to fight.
If my generation cannot do it, the next one
will.
We will do everything to stop it on my generation.
We have achieved freedom and security for
Ukrainians, Chechens and other peoples who
are now under occupation.
Join us, fight for your freedom.
It is difficult to take, it has a high price.
43:20 Interviewer: Looking at how Ukraine
is supported by Europe, America, the whole
world.
I think that in your head and in your people
there is such an opinion that "if we were
given such support, we would tear the Muscovites
apart.
Fighter: If we had such help then, there would
not be such bloodshed in Ukraine today, because
Russia would not be able to go further.
There would be no terrible illusions that
they are so terrible, destroying everything.
It would have been a
state that lost to the Chechens.
And Ukrainians would not have perceived them
as a threat.
They would not have been able to crush them
morally.
44:11 Interviewer: There are still people
in Russia who will say that Chechens are terrorists
(Plan North East).
The FSB blew up houses.
Who knows the facts.
I advise everyone to read the book "FSB blows
up Russia".
Competition:
Today among you we will play the book "FSB
undermines Russia", which describes the whole
essence of Putin's power in order to take
it away, you just need to subscribe to the
channel and put a like!
And drop a link to the cool tiktok of the
Kadyrovites and describe what the catch is,
manipulation.
The best option is to take a book, so let's
get involved.
There is a lot of material.
Interviewer: At the same time, Northeast,
we talked to you, the Chechens captured just
people who were sitting there.
What kind of action was it?
It's not a setup, it's really your people.
A fighter: It was an action of desperation.
Because every time they seized different buildings,
there was only one demand
- to withdraw troops from Chechnya.
They did not ask for money, they did not even
ask to let them go.
They wanted the withdrawal of troops to save
their people from destruction.
They did not want their people to live in
slavery.
They were ready to sacrifice their lives.
Of course, the world perceived it as terrorism.
The world refused to support us.
It was easier for them to just recognize us
as terrorists.
The world hoped back then, as always in history,
that Russia would change.
It has never changed in its history.
It will not change.
Ukraine sees and feels it today.
46:20 President of Ichkeria:
Ordinary Russism is worse than fascism and
Nazism, racism, all human ideologies that
are built on hatred.
They are nurtured by the highest rank of Russian
statehood.
Russians believe neither in Christ, nor in
Mohammed, nor in Buda, nor in anyone.
46:38 Interviewer: You are a Ukrainian who
fights in Dudayev's battalion.
Why?
Kep - Fighter: First of all, this is a group
I knew before the war.
They are friends.
Not much has changed since the beginning of
the war.
It's just that this team was militarized and
became one big unit.
It is this battalion.
Historically, my friends, their parents, they
are from Ichkeria.
Their fathers fought in the first and second
campaigns.
Obviously, with the beginning of the war here,
it became a battalion unit.
By this coincidence, I am now here with my
friends.
47:20 Interviewer: What did the representatives
of Ichkeria teach you in terms of life philosophy,
because these people are always very deep,
from those I know.
What exactly did they teach you?
A fighter: Discipline is the main thing I
took from these people.
Purity of spirit and intentions.
It is everywhere and in everything.
These people are absolutely transparent and
without guile in their actions.
There is something to learn from them in terms
of discipline, self-control.
The philosophy of views on life is also common.
Attitude to death and life.
For these people, death is an everyday thing.
They do not find in it something that an ordinary
person is in a stupor.
For them, it is just perishability, all life
is a moment that passes and is followed by
the next life that a person deserves.
Either paradise or hyena, which a person will
feed himself.
Therefore, I borrowed the lightness of attitude
to death from these people.
The most important thing for me was to emphasize
that life is a moment that you just need to
live with dignity, to go this way with dignity.
And then go to where my place will be in the
next life.
Our battalion, our group is international:
mostly Chechens, Ukrainians, Crimean Tatars,
Azerbaijanis.
There are people representing other nationalities
who want to join us.
Here no one divides anyone into nations, races
and so on.
People here are united by one idea and one
incentive
to fight for freedom and independence of their
nations.
But now Ukraine is an opportunity to realize
our plans.
That is, here we can all prove ourselves,
our ideas.
To achieve freedom of our peoples with one
common fist.
So that sooner or later these people could
come to their land and return their traditions
that have been there for centuries.
But with the advent of Putin's power everywhere
there is absolute chaos, violence, destruction
of peoples.
In order to defeat the common enemy, it is
necessary to unite, consolidate the peoples.
Therefore, I would advise all people who watch
us only one thing: to find like-minded people,
people close in spirit, to take up arms, to
come and just fight for freedom.
Because if there is no resistance here, the
war will go on and on.
To other regions, to other countries.
I advise everyone only one thing: to fight
for freedom and independence, to adhere to
their ideals, to follow their own path.
I would advise young people: read, develop,
take the right path and keep going.
50:29 President of Ichkeria:
In vain Russians think that now they will
intimidate the world, humanity with their
army, criminal authorities, nuclear weapons.
They will not intimidate.
50:39 Interviewer: Now your people are being
persecuted again, thrown at us.
That is, there is this population that still
lives on the territory of Ichkeria.
It is under the regime of Kadyrov.
This is a totalitarian regime.
I know that for any criticism they simply
take people to the forest and beat them, mock
them, then make them say on camera that "Shaitan
confused" and so on.
There are people who protest against this
mobilization.
I often hear such words as "Why won't Chechnya
stand up?", because I understand that no one
wants to go here and fight.
They are now mobilizing people, many representatives
of your nationality have already been killed.
What to do with this?
Is there a chance that people will stand up
and remove Kadyrov?
Or is everyone so intimidated that there is
no point in standing up?
A fighter: Look.
When I am asked this question, I ask a counter
question.
When I am asked: "Why is there no uprising
in Chechnya, Dagestan, somewhere else", I
always ask a question: "Why is there no uprising
in Donetsk?
Luhansk?
Kherson?
In Melitopol?
In Mariupol?
Why is there no uprising there?"
You see, the Chechen people lost 300 thousand.
It's like 14 million Ukrainians would have
died out of 40 million.
The regime that is there now...
Yes, the Russian army is stolen, corrupted,
it is not the second army of the world, but
Russian bodies like the FSB, the Ministry
of Internal Affairs, believe me, they are
very strong.
They have created such terror, such horror
in the occupied territories, because I talked
to those Ukrainians who left Mariupol, Melitopol.
What they tell me is just horror...
Those who ask such questions should go there
at least once and live either in Chechnya,
or in Melitopol, or in Mariupol for at least
a week.
This question will immediately disappear.
If there is such a cruel, terrible, cannibalistic
regime in Chechnya today...
The last thing they have to do is to take
the dissatisfied and throw them into boiling
vats of oil in the center of Grozny.
They have already done everything else.
They have already applied all executions and
tortures to Chechens.
Chechnya is in fact a huge concentration camp.
A huge terrible concentration camp.
There was a rally in Grozny, about 120 women
turned out.
Kadyrov, not knowing what else to do, said
that all male relatives of these women would
go to Ukraine to fight without any training.
If he knows how, if he does not know how - it
does not matter, he will be thrown to the
front line.
They will choose the place where the Ukrainian
artillery best blows up the positions, send
him there and tell him to die.
And he will die.
This is fate.
I constantly give Europeans an example of
Chechens who are mobilized here.
I say "if Ukraine was captured, believe me:
they would send here not only 10 thousand
Chechens out of 800 thousand.
Imagine how many people they would have armed
with Mosin rifles and easily sent them to
Poland, Romania, Slovakia".
They would claim that the Ukrainian People's
Republic, for example, is doing it.
The Russians would again have nothing to do
with it.
This is the fate of faithful torn peoples.
Among Chechens there are some idiots who believe
in all this Kadyrov's nonsense.
But there are few of them.
Ukraine should somehow respond to this.
It would be very nice if they recognized independence.
Now they are holding a referendum.
That's good.
Donbas, Luhansk, Kherson peoples do not exist
in the world.
But there are Chechen, Tatar, Yakut peoples.
But according to Bandera, "free peoples have
free countries".
55:29 Interviewer: What is the ideal scenario
for you?
Is it the victory of Ukraine, the collapse
of Russia, the independence of these nations?
Fighter: The ideal scenario for us is that
Ukraine becomes a moderator of the former
post-Soviet space.
The Chechen Armed Forces become part of NATO.
We have to be in NATO.
We all want to be in NATO.
All North Caucasian nations should be part
of NATO.
There is no other way out.
Association and membership in the European
Union is necessary because we want to be in
normal alliances with normal alliances.
No CSTO, no CIS.
We do not want to be with the
Russians.
We are tired, they are crazy people.
They want a tsar, then they do not want.
They have God, then they don't.
They have private property, then they don't.
This is an alcoholic neighbor with serious
mental problems.
One day he breaks your front door with an
axe, and the next day he kneels on your doorstep
and apologizes, swearing that he will not
do it again.
They are inadequate as a people and a country.
Historically, under any system and ideology
- "Whatever we do, we get the Communist Party".
In any case, we get a concentration camp.
This or another.
Just the sign on this concentration camp changes.
Lenin said that this is the prison of the
peoples.
Today, Navalny, Khodorkovsky, Gudkov and other
Russian oppositionists - they are here in
Ukraine, in the West, asking to preserve a
single indivisible Russia.
It sounds strange to me.
They talk about their beautiful Russia of
the future, and we call it the damned Russia
of the future.
They propose in this prison of peoples to
simply change the bars, locks, doors and paint
the walls pink.
Interviewer: Let's put the TV on.
Fighter: Yes, and we will make cosmetic repairs
and everything will be fine.
In fact, the problem is much deeper.
In any case, they will deceive the West, because
they will simply reformat.
And the West will believe, as always, saying
that these are different Russians.
In 30-40 years they will reform the army.
Navalny will make his army without corruption,
without anything and will go to Ukraine.
Watch the debate between Strelkov and Navalny
on YouTube.
Navalny: The war you started is expensive.
It is destroying Russia's economy.
I see important points in the Minsk agreements
for all of us: language, the status of Donbass.
Fighter: Strelkov proposes to throw a nuclear
bomb tomorrow, and Navalny proposes the day
after tomorrow, when he will build a normal
state machine, army, and later we will deal
with the world.
Khodorkovsky served 9 years in prison and
on the very first day he said in an interview
that he was ready to take up arms and go to
war in the North Caucasus.
He just did not know that Kadyrov was already
there.
Seriously, in prison he was limited in terms
of information.
59:45 Khodorkovsky: "I think war is very bad,
but if we are talking about the division of
the North Caucasus, then war means war.
I would go to war."
He's a fighter: He says sincerely that he
is ready to go to war.
The presenter asks: "What will you fight for
there?"
For our Russian land.
She says that it is Chechen land, it is a
different people, a different culture.
He says that it is Russian land because our
ancestors conquered it.
We will not give it back, he says.
And then he sheds tears in front of Gordon
and apologizes to Ukrainians.
The Russian opposition hates Putin, but not
for the war, but for losing it.
1:00:36 Khodorkovsky: I can't see it.
Fighter: If "Kyiv in 2 Days" was released,
everything would be fine.
Believe me, he would be a hero for them.
There would be no claims to him.
The proof is the war in Georgia.
When the super oppositionist Navalny: "Let's
hit the rats, we need to hit the General Staff
with a missile, we need this, this and this".
1:01:04 Sobchak: Did you call for the recognition
of Abkhazia as independent?
Navalny: Manifesto of the "People" movement.
Abkhazia was independent from Georgia, it
cannot be compared with Crimea and Ukraine.
Fighter: For us, for you there are no good
ones on the other side.
Independent Tatarstan, Ichkeria, Yakutia,
Dagestan can be good for us.
But we have no choice yet.
As long as they are who they are, we have
no choice.
We cannot guarantee our children, grandchildren
a normal future, a peaceful sky above our
heads, normal human relations.
Interviewer: Are there people in your country
who can rise up?
I understand that many generations have already
left, they are abroad, like you, for example.
France, all of Europe in general is their
refuge now.
The last shootings were in 2016, the last
armed conflict against Kadyrov's government
in Ichkeria.
Are there any guerrillas?
For example, in the forests, who will come,
stand up if necessary.
One Russian, who is fighting for us, said
that Chechens are already the same as Russians.
They are used to living in this evil empire.
Fighter: An example of how a Russian still
remains hostage to his thinking wherever he is.
They said the same thing about Ukrainians.
"Ukrainians are like us, just a different
dialect, southern Russian".
As long as at least one of us and you who
disagrees with them is alive, they will not
win, they will not succeed.
There are a million of you now, tens of millions,
we are less, but we will make trouble for
them, as it was before.
God willing, we will get the freedom.
We have different worldviews.
Both Chechens and Ukrainians want freedom.
I have never met anyone else.
None of us wants to seize anything from you.
But Russians do.
They have problems with their heads.
They do not understand that there can be other
people like in the USA or in Europe.
The world thinks that it should be aligned
to them, be convenient for them.
Therefore, no one ever gives up on us.
Thank God, Ukraine has President Zelensky,
Commander-in-Chief Valeriy Zaluzhny.
There are serious, powerful leaders at the
head of the people.
They go into battle and competently strike
the enemy.
Now the Russians are even talking not about
the capture of Ukraine, but about the salvation
of Russia.
1:07:48 Interviewer: Why is Kadyrov so beneficial
to Putin?
Few people allow themselves as much as he
does.
Plus, Chechens are also intimidated.
Fighter: Look, the phenomenon of Kadyrov is
that no one agreed to this role of a puppet
except him.
They chose an inadequate and stupid man and
made him a legendary image of a great warrior,
a PR promotion.
The main thing during the investigation is
not to come out on ourselves.
Ramzan tells a story about Shamil Basayev.
One Russian even filed a lawsuit, saying why
Kadyrov and not him.
When Kadyrov's men were thrown here to Kyiv,
they were hit on the head like never before.
Because they are not soldiers, army or a kind
of troops, they are punishers.
Kadyrovets: We are following in the footsteps
of Banderites and Nazis, after the so-called
regiment of Dzhokhar
Dudayev ..
1:10:02 Fighter: They followed the Russian
army to kill, to rape, to shoot tiktoks.
They can't do anything else, they are not
an army, they are punitive units consisting
of sadists.
There were 40 thousand of them for the whole
Chechen people.
Interviewer: Why do young people go to these
punishers?
Is it about money or what is this story about?
You have such educated people.
Why do they follow Shaitan?
Fighter: They are the Shaitans themselves
There are punishers in every nation.
They agree to serve for any money.
They sold themselves, like in that song.
They liked the advertising of the Russian
army, but they will be disappointed.
Because when the Russian economy falls, there
will be no more opportunities, it is akeady
going down.
This is Putin's personal guard.
When some riots and rallies begin in Moscow,
the police will simply shoot 200 thousand
people.
But when a million people come out, they will
be afraid.
For the Kadyrovites, if there are 10 million,
they will not flinch.
They will carry out the order, this is Putin's
last chance.
He counts on them, although they disgraced
themselves as soldiers near Kyiv.
Some of them still sit here or ride here,
but in general, most of them follow orders
at home.
They do not go to the fighting, but they shoot
deserters.
However, Chechens themselves are mobilized,
families are taken hostage.
They will leave everyone.
They have hidden in the decree on mobilization
the 7th paragraph on the number of mobilized.
These are his personal guards, dogs who are
ready to tear up everyone without weapons,
those who will not be able to resist.
1:13:19 Interviewer: All the soldiers of Dudayev's
battalion are fighting in Ukraine at their
own expense, but the battalion needs support,
because these are all constant expenses: food,
fuel, ammunition.
So if you have the opportunity, and most
importantly the desire to support the battalion,
I will leave the link to the account in the
description of this video.
Let's support our brothers.
1:13:41 Soldiers: But for the donations you
gave us for fuel we came to a wonderful village,
which was under occupation until today.
Now it is not anymore.
Keep sending us money, we will be very grateful
to you.
With each donation, more and more people will
be free.
Amen.
1:13:58 Interviewer: You know, now more and
more often I catch myself thinking that we
are living in war, while, for example, in
Italy people think about football, go shopping,
enjoy life.
Your people are the same.
The French did not believe Ukrainians who
talked about Russians.
"These are 19th century methods," - they said.
Why is there such injustice in the world?
Someone lives peacefully, and we are under
this pressure.
A fighter: Let's look at it from the other
side.
For the first time in history, the Ukrainian
army defended Kyiv, the capital, chases the
enemy, reduces the number of occupied territories,
expands the liberated territories.
Interviewer: The price of all this?
Human lives.
A fighter: Okay.
The world is a cruel place.
A man is born in agony and dies not of his
own free will.
There are values above comfort, good car,
house, beer.
For these values there is a price that Ukraine
pays.
Interviewer: Why do our peoples pay it?
A fighter: Historically.
We did not unite against the Russians many
centuries ago.
If we had not allowed the Russians to expand
their empire, we would not be sitting here
in front of the cameras, we would be sitting
in
a football stadium.
Now we have to do it.
So that our children, grandchildren, great-grandchildren
do not ask each other this question.
Someone has to do it.
Everyone fought for their history: Italy,
Germany, Britain.
Interviewer: But we are constantly struggling...
Fighter: Neither you nor we have won the empire
completely.
Interviewer: It will be endless.
Putin will die, a new generation will be born.
A fighter: That is why we are here.
To build everything on our example, on the
example of Belarusians.
Russia without national regions is small.
This process should be completed with the
complete demilitarization of Russia.
Police and internal troops and that's all.
It should not be like in Germany.
We must not allow the opposition to power
in the same way, because they profess imperialism.
Russia should be divided into sectors.
Denazification should be carried out.
It always attacks, it does not defend.
I want to say a big thank you to the Ukrainian
authorities, the Armed Forces of Ukraine,
the Ukrainian people for what they do.
It is a source of pride.
It is an honor to be with you
at this moment.
Without you we have little chance to liberate
our homeland, and without us you have little
chance to live long in a peaceful country.
Because they will return on any pretext in
any case.
It is inevitable.
Interviewer: Will there be a second war after
the first one?
A fighter: Yes.
Absolutely.
If the dispossessed peoples do not get freedom,
Russia will return, and we will have little
chance.
Russia must be in its historical borders.
We are not cannibals.
They are.
We just want to live freely.
Dear friends, I hope you found this material
interesting, you can let me know in the comments.
Very deep thoughts about our nations.
Ukrainian and Nakh.
How much Russia oppressed us for centuries.
I am not surprised that these guys are
with us now.
I invite you to support the petition to the
President of Ukraine.
To recognize the independence of the Republic
of Ichkeria.
The link is in
the description.
It is the easiest thing you can do.
Dear Ukrainians!
We have united with our brotherly nations
against the common enemy who is trying to
destroy us.
All Crimean Tatars who were mobilized, I suggest
you
to surrender.
We
will come soon to our lands.
Greetings to all the people of Ichkeria.
I
want to appeal to all mobilized guys who were
brought here by force.
Surrender.
Come to our side.
The journalist Yelena Milashina, who is very
unpleasant to me, also sits in the interview
with Sobchak and says: "That's it, Chechen
ways and laws are
destroyed, we have broken them".
Sobchak asks her if it is true, and she says
"yes".
I showed them a gesture.
The fact that we are here, hundreds of thousands
of people like us can show them what they broke us.
The Soviet government broke us for 70 years.
People read our Korans in basements so that
no one could see.
They mocked us as much as they could, until
89 they were sure that they finally succeeded.
We assimilated, became like them, because
they raised a sufficient number of Chechen
intellectuals for whom Russian was their native
language.
Dzhokhar Dudayev came and said: "Let's go".
And we go.
We always broke them in their stories.
We had a national hero.
Baysangur of Benuela.
There was a legend that he was born after
the death of Sheikh Mansour.
We do not give up and you do not give up.
It is impossible.
That is why all Russians, those who are for
you, those who are against you, politicians,
oppositionists - think the same about you
and us.
But they are wrong.
Russians have been destroying our history
for centuries, it is a sin to die for them.
We will liberate our land.
Glory to the nation!
Death to enemies!